Register of the Allen Drury papers 65007.4088171
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1932-1995.
  - Courage and Hesitation (1971) (Box 47)
    - Review by Elizabeth Drew, 1971 (Folder 47: 7)
  - The Throne of Saturn (1971)
    - Notes, undated (Folder 47: 8)
    - Typescript, undated (Folder 47: 9)
    - Typescript, undated (Box-folder 48: 1-3)
    - Galley proofs, undated (Folder 48: 4)
    - Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 49: 1)
    - Pre-publication advertising flyer drafts, 1970 (Folder 49: 2)
  - "Richard and the Elves," New York Times, 1971 September 29. (Folder 49: 3)
  - "Inside the White House 1971," Look, 1971 October 19. (Folder 49: 4)
  - Newspaper articles relating to George McGovern, 1972. (Folder 49: 5)
    Clippings and typescript
  - "Road Looks Clear Ahead in GOP Bid," Orlando Sentinel, 1972 March 12. (Folder 49: 6)
    Typescript and printed copy
  - Introduction for Hester Chapman, Rollins Writers Conference, 1972 November 10. (Folder 49: 7)
  - Come Nineveh, Come Tyre (1973)
    - Typescript, 1973 (Folder 49: 8-10)
    - Galley proofs, 1973 (Box-folder 50: 1-3)
  - Remarks at the Friends of the Library, Orland, Florida, 1974 May 15. (Folder 50: 4)
  - The Promise of Joy (1975)
    - Typescript, 1975 (Folder 50: 5-6)
    - Typescript, 1975 (Box-folder 51: 1)
    - Galley proofs, 1975 (Folder 51: 2)
  - A God against the Gods (1976)
    - Typescript, undated (Folder 51: 3-6)
    - Typescript, undated (Box-folder 52: 1-3)
    - Galley proofs, undated (Folder 52: 4)
  - Anna Hastings (1977), typescript, undated (Folder 52: 5-6)
  - Return to Thebes (1977) (Box 53)
    - Typescript, undated (Folder 53: 1-4)
    - Galley proofs, undated (Folder 53: 5-6)
    - Galley proofs, undated (Box-folder 54: 1)
    - Press release, 1977 February 27 (Folder 54: 2)
  - Mark Coffin, U.S.S. (1979)
    - Typescript, undated (Folder 54: 3-5)
    - Galley proofs, 1978 (Folder 54: 6)
    - Galley proofs, 1978 (Box-folder 55: 1)
    - Reviews
      - General, 1979 (Folder 55: 2)
      - Bancroft, Griffing, 1979 (Folder 55: 3)
  - Egypt: The Eternal Smile (1980)
    - Typescript, 1980 (Folder 55: 4)
    - Printed copy, 1980 (Folder 55: 5)
    - Reviews, 1980-1981 (Folder 55: 6)
  - The Hill of Summer (1981)
    - Typescript, undated (Folder 55: 7)
    - Typescript, undated (Box-folder 56: 1-6)
    - Typescript, undated (Box-folder 57: 1-3)
    - Galley proofs, undated (Folder 57: 4-6)
    - Galley proofs, undated (Box-folder 58: 1)
    - Correspondence, 1981 (Folder 58: 2)
    - Reviews, 1982 (Folder 58: 3)
  - "Edith Mirrielees," Stanford Magazine, 1982 Summer. (Folder 58: 4)
  - Decision (1983)
    - Notes, undated (Folder 58: 5)
    - Typescript, 1983 (Folder 58: 6-7)
    - Typescript, 1983 (Box-folder 59: 1)
    - Galley proofs, 1983 (Folder 59: 2-3)
    - Correspondence, 1983 (Folder 59: 4)
    - List of promotional copies sent, 1983 (Folder 59: 5)
    - Note to the reader, undated (Folder 59: 6)
    - Reviews, 1983 (Box-folder 60: 1)
    - Synopsis, 1983. (Folder 60: 2)
  - "The Role and Responsibilities of the News Media," Forty-third Arizona Town Hall, Grand Canyon, 1983 October 24. (Folder 60: 3)
  - The Roads of Earth (1984)
    - Working notes, 1983 (Folder 60: 4)
    - Typescript, undated (Folder 60: 5-7)
    - Typescript, undated (Box-folder 61: 1)
    - Galley proofs, undated (Folder 61: 2)
  - "Miracle of Madness," California Living Magazine, 1984 July 15. (Folder 61: 3)
  - Pentagon (1986)
    - Notes, 1984-1986 (Folder 61: 4)
    - Typescript, undated (Folder 61: 5-7)
    - Typescript, undated (Box-folder 62: 1-6)
    - Typescript, undated (Box-folder 63: 1-5)
    - Correspondence, 1984-1986 (Folder 63: 6)
    - List of characters, undated (Box-folder 64: 1)
  - "Alive and Well at 200," Ford Times, 1987 September. (Folder 64: 2)
  - "Lakeside," Bohemian Grove, 1989 July 18. (Folder 64: 3)
  - Toward What Bright Glory? (1990)
    - Notes, undated (Folder 64: 4)
    - Typescript, undated (Folder 64: 5-7)
    - Typescript, undated (Box-folder 65: 1-6)
    - Typescript, undated (Box-folder 66: 1-4)
    - Galley proofs, 1990 (Folder 66: 5-6)
    - Galley proofs, 1990 (Box-folder 67: 1)
    - Printed copy, 1990 (Folder 67: 2-6)
    - Printed copy, 1990 (Box-folder 68: 1-6)
  - Into What Far Harbor? (1993), typescript, undated (Box-folder 69: 1-6)
  - Into What Far Harbor? (1993), typescript, undated (Box-folder 70: 1-2)
  - A Thing of State (1995), typescript, undated (Folder 70: 3-6)
  - A Thing of State (1995), typescript, undated (Box-folder 71: 1-3)
- Memorabilia, undated
  U.S. Army military identification tags and Rotary Club International cloth standard
  - U.S. army military identification tags (2), undated (Folder 71: 4)
  - Rotary International Club No. 960, Porterville, California, cloth standard, undated (Folder 71: 5)
- Card Index, undated (Box 72)
  Arranged alphabetically by subject
  - Index cards referring to various subjects discussed in the United States Senate, undated
- Photographs, 1928-1992. (Photo file, Box 73)
  Prints depicting Allen Drury at various stages of his life, and associates and friends of Allen Drury
  - 28 portrait prints of Allen Drury, 1950-1968, undated (Photo-file A)
  - 10 prints of Allen Drury at various public events, with celebrities including Otto Preminger and Joan Crawford, 1959-1967, undated (Photo-file B)
  - 10 prints of Allen Drury with public figures, including President Lyndon and Lady Bird Johnson, Earl Warren, Dwight Eisenhower, and Alben W. Barkley, 1944-1964, undated (Photo-file C)
  - 9 portrait photographs of President Richard Nixon, Spiro Agnew, Colonel Walter Phillips, Wayne Morse, Senator George A. Wilson, Ivy B. Priest, and others, 1941-1960, undated (Photo-file D)
  - 30 prints of Allen Drury with family and personal friends and colleagues, 1934-1969. (Photo-file E)
    Includes photograph of Drury's work table, undated
  - 7 portrait prints of Allen Drury, 1 pint of Senator Robert Taft, and 1 print of Drury's book A Shade of Difference, 1962, undated (Photo-file mF)
  - 10 prints depicting Allen Drury and others, 1958-1983, undated (Photo-file G)
  - 23 prints depicting Allen Drury at various stages of his life, 1948-1990, undated (Box-folder 73: 1-2)
  - 3 prints depicting Allen Drury in the United States army, 1942 (Folder 73: 3)
  - 19 prints depicting Allen Drury's parents, 1950-1967, undated (Folder 73: 4)
  - 7 prints depicting Allen Drury's grandparents and other family members, 1928-1960, undated (Folder 73: 5)
  - 5 prints depicting Allen Drury's sister, Ann Killiany, and her family, 1958-1976, undated (Folder 73: 6)
  - 4 prints of Allen Drury and William H. Eichstadt, undated (Folder 73: 7)
  - 2 prints depicting President Lyndon and Lady bird Johnson and Allen Drury, 1968, undated (Folder 73: 8)
  - 19 prints of Allen Drury with various celebrities, including the Apollo Space Mission team, Carol Channing, Norman Mailer, and Elsa Lanchester, 1961-1990, undated (Folder 73: 9)
  - 11 prints depicting Allen Drury and friends, 1960-1992 (Folder 73: 10)
  - 4 prints of Allen Drury and others at political conventions in the United States, 1972-1984 (Folder 73: 11)
  - 14 prints of Allen Drury and others on various trips, 1960-1992, undated (Folder 73: 12)
  - 2 prints of Allen Drury and others in China, 1984 (Folder 73: 13)
  - 6 prints of Allen Drury and others in South Africa, 1966 (Folder 73: 14)
  - 7 prints of Allen Drury and others in Taiwan, 1984-1988 (Folder 73: 15)
  - 2 prints of Allen Drury and others at the Bohemian Grove encampment, 1967-1976 (Folder 73: 16)
  - 4 prints of Allen Drury and others at the Advise and Consent play and motion picture openings, undated (Folder 73: 17)
  - 2 prints of Allen Drury being sworn in at the National Council on the Arts, 1983 February (Folder 73: 18)
  - 9 prints of Allen Drury at his home at 480 Ridge Road, Tiburon, California, 1967-1984 (Folder 73: 19)
  - 13 prints of Allen Drury at his home at Fort Foote Road, Fort Washington, Maryland, 1955 (Folder 73: 20)
  - 1 print depicting the United States Senate Foreign Relations Committee hearing of State Department nominations, 1944 December 14 (Folder 73: 21)
- Sound Recordings, 1970-1988 (Record cabinet, Cassette cabinet, Box 73)
  Interviews and speeches of Allen Drury on sound discs and compact sound cassettes
  - Cassettes 1-3, Sound recording of the Larry King Show, 1982 June 15 (Reading room workstation)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Use copy reference number: 65007_a_0003680
    This is a radio broadcast recording of Larry King interviewing Allen Drury upon the release of his newest book, The Hill of Summer. They discuss Drury's progression from journalist to literary author, the writing process, character creation, novelistic treatment of political orientation, the film adaptation of Advise and Consent, the form of the political novel, writing habits, and The Hill of Summer. They end with 90 minutes of caller questions. (3 compact sound cassettes)
  - Cassettes 4-6, Sound recording of the Larry King Show, 1983 August 17 (Reading room workstation)
    Use copy reference number: 65007_a_0003687
    This is a radio broadcast recording of Larry King interviewing Allen Drury upon the release of his newest book, Decision. They discuss Drury's progression from journalist to literary author, the writing process behind Decision, Drury's personal politics and the politics reflected in his novels, editing, writing habits, thoughts on Central America, the state of media journalism, and his decision to live in California. They end with 90 minutes of caller questions. (3 compact sound cassettes)
  - Cassette 7, An American faith: 41 years on Capitol Hill, 1984 October 12 (Reading room workstation)
    Use copy reference numbers: 65007_a_0003708 and 65007_a_0003691
    In this address at the Commonwealth Club of California in San Francisco, Allen Drury discusses his label as a conservative author, the three major themes in his books, the human element of the American democratic system, his attitudes towards the Soviet Union and Soviet imperialism, and the threat of nuclear war. Arguing that we should not yield to the Soviets, he advocates for long range civil defense planning, and cautions against letting fear dictate our response to the "Soviet problem." Shirley Temple Black conducts the question and answer session following Drury's address. (There are two copies of this recording that differ in their completeness; the more complete one was digitized by Hoover as file 65007_a_0003708.)
  - Cassette 8, Sound recording of a ceremony honoring the Battle of Leyte Gulf, 1984 October 31 (Reading room workstation)
    Use copy reference number: 65007_a_0003692
    This is a recording of the 40th anniversary ceremony commemorating the Battle of Leyte Gulf. United States Secretary of Defense Caspar Weinberger provides the opening remarks, discussing the battle for liberation in the Philippine Sea led by Douglas MacArthur. Jean MacArthur is presented with the Secretary of Defense Medal for Distinguished Public Service. U.S. Secretary of the Army John Otho Marsh, Jr., and Benjamin Romualdez, the Philippine ambassador, also briefly reflect on the event.
  - Cassette 9, Sound recording of an interview with U.S. General Charles Gabriel, 1984 June 13 (Reading room workstation)
    Use copy reference number: 65007_a_0003694
    Allen Drury interviews General Charles Gabriel about how the Pentagon works, as part of Drury's research for his next novel. Drury considers framing the prospective book's central narrative around a proposed missile system or a "specific mission of some sort." In his response, Gabriel describes his primary duties on the U.S. Joint Chiefs of Staff, the logisitics of general military operations, and his thoughts on the Soviets. The sound quality of this recording is fairly poor.
  - Cassette 10, Sound recording of an interview with U.S. General John Wickham Jr., 1984 August 9 (Reading room workstation)
    Use copy reference number: 65007_a_0003697
    Allen Drury interviews General John Wickham Jr., United States Army Chief of Staff, as part of Drury's research for his next novel. Among other topics, Wickham describes his four main functions as steward of the army, how he deals with other joint chiefs and the constant turnover in the civilian secretary system, military pay, the state of the military, and his thoughts on the Soviets. The sound quality of this recording is fairly poor.
  - Cassette 11, Sound recording of an interview with U.S. Secretary of the Air Force Verne Orr, undated (Reading room workstation)
    Use copy reference number: 65007_a_0003699
    Allen Drury interviews Verne Orr, United States Secretary of the Air Force, as part of Drury's research for his next novel. Among other topics, Orr describes the Air Force's relationship with the other branches of the military, the speed at which weapons projects are approved, the weapons testing process, and his thoughts on the Soviets. He takes issue with the ease at which information is given to the Soviets, particularly through academic channels. The sound quality of this recording is fairly poor.
  - Cassette 12, Sound recording of an interview with U.S. Secretary of the Navy John Lehman, 1984 November 1 (Reading room workstation)
    Use copy reference number: 65007_a_0003700
    Allen Drury interviews John Lehman, United States Secretary of the Navy, as part of Drury's research for his next novel. Among other topics, Lehman describes where the navy has been and where it is going, relationships between the branches, how the navy has changed under the Reagan administration, his thoughts on the Soviets and their naval fleet, and his desire to change "some fundamental institutional aspects of the navy and marine corps" by instilling a concern for leadership and strategy. The sound quality of this recording is fairly poor.
  - Cassette 13, Sound recording of Allen Drury dictated correspondence and a lecture, 1970 October 1 (Reading room workstation)
    Use copy reference number: 65007_a_0003703
    This Allen Drury cassette recording contains undated, dictated correspondence to various parties, and a Drury lecture to an unidentified audience in 1970. In the lecture, Drury gives a brief personal biography before fielding politically oriented questions from the audience. The sound quality of the lecture is fairly poor.
  - #14, United States Senate Republican conference, "U.S.S.R.: A Clear and Present Danger?" with Allen Drury and Senator Hayakawa, undated (Reading room workstation)
    Use copy reference number: 65007_a_0003706
    In a series of five programs of about two minutes in length, Senator S. I. Hayakawa, Chairman of the Senate Foreign Relations Subcommittee on East Asian and Pacific Affairs, interviews Allen Drury on a number of topics in the wake of his most recent novel, The Hill of Summer. They discuss Soviet military writings represented in Drury's novels, the military dangers of a young Soviet leadership, Drury's tendency to map current events to possible end game scenarios, American media attitudes towards the Soviet military threat, and Reagan's moves to counter the threat.
  - Sound recording of an interview with Allen Drury conducted by Diane Rehm, 1983 August 17 (Reading room workstation)
    Use copy reference number: 65007_a_0003710
    On her morning talk show show, Kaleidoscope, Diane Rehm interviews Allen Drury upon the release of his newest novel, Decision. Among other topics, they discuss the novel's theme of capital punishment, the idea process, writer's block, Drury's journalist training, the genesis of Advise and Consent and its reception by politicians and critics. The show ends with caller questions.
  - Sound recording of Allen Drury dictated correspondence, undated (Reading room workstation)
    Use copy reference number: 65007_a_0003712
    This Allen Drury cassette recording contains undated, dictated correspondence to various parties. Correspondence concerning the research and subsequent fan appreciation of the novel The Throne of Saturn, receives particular attention.
  - Sound recording of an unidentified Allen Drury speech, 1982 December (Reading room workstation)
    Use copy reference number: 65007_a_0003714
    This undated cassette features an incomplete and nearly unintelligible Allen Drury speech of unknown provenance.
  - Interview for Pentagon, with Tom Winston, KABL, undated (Box-folder 73: 22)
  - Interview with Mike Savage, ABC, "The Best of Double Talk,", undated (Folder 73: 23)
  - Trip to Alaska, undated (Folder 73: 24)
  - Trip to Alaska, research for proposed book, undated (Folder 73: 25-26)
  - Trip to Alaska, 1977 July-August (Folder 73: 27)
  - Interview, 1978 March 24 (Folder 73: 28)
  - National Council on the Arts meeting, 1988 August (Folder 73: 29)
  - Sound recording of Allen Drury appeal for election to the United States Congress, undated (Reading room workstation)
    Use copy reference numbers: 65007_a_0002258 and 65007_a_0005693
    Drury appeals to the citizens of a congressional district to send him to Washington as their representative in Congress. He believes his two years as a journalist have shown him how the incumbent is lacking and how he could do better. There may be two copies of this recording, each on two discs. Two of the four discs have labels "United States Recording Co. / Washington, D.C. / Allen Drury / original" while two others have labels "Allen Drury / dubbed copy."
  - A Moment with Mr. Allen Drury sound recording, 1963 November 2 (Reading room workstation)
    Use copy reference number: 65007_a_0005694
    Allen Drury is interviewed about his books. The interviewer asks questions that refer to her "viewers", so this interview was likely conducted for a visual medium, although this is only a sound recording. (1 disc)
- Videorecordings, 1986-1991 (Box 74, Tape cabinet)
  Interviews and speeches of Allen Drury, and other subject material of interest to Allen Drury, on VHS videocassettes
  - Interview, Atlantic Center for the Arts, 1986 June (Tape cabinet)
  - "Inside Story with Slim Goodby,", undated (Tape cabinet)
  - United States Senate hearing, undated (Box-folder 74: 1)
  - Interview and speech at Sacramento City College, 1986 November 6 (Folder 74: 2)
  - Premier Yu, Taiwan, 1988 April (Folder 74: 3)
  - Interview, Writers Forum and Book Review, television presentation, 1991 May 19 (Folder 74: 4)
- Incremental Materials (Box 75)